Guide to the Franklin B. Dexter, Secretary of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Franklin B. Dexter, secretary of Yale University, records
1833-1910
RU 51
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
(3 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and related materials concerning Yale Corporation affairs, scholarships and prizes, honorary degrees, and other activities administered by the secretary's office during the tenure of Franklin B. Dexter, 1869-1899.
Yale University. Office of the Secretary
Dexter, Franklin Bowditch, 1842-1920
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-A (YRG 4-A), Records of the Yale secretary's office.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, and related materials concerning Yale Corporation affairs, scholarships and prizes, honorary degrees, and other activities administered by the secretary's office during the tenure of Franklin B. Dexter, 1869-1899.
Degrees, Academic; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale Corporation; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Awards; Yale University -- Degrees; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University. Office of the Secretary
- Records of Franklin B. Dexter, 1869-1899; Accession 1933-A-003
  - Correspondence, 1872-1887 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1876-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, 1883-1899 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, re: admission, 1846-1897 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yale Corporation: correspondence, 1881-1899 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fellows of the Corporation: nominations and election, 1836-1899 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fellows of the Corporation: miscellaneous correspondence, 1872-1899 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous letters of thanks to the Corporation, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and lands: plans and suggestions, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yale Bicentennial Committee, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's Office: list of investments and expenses, Circa 1887 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Faculty appointments and promotions, 1884-1899 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fellowships, scholarships, and prizes, 1879-1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Art School: correspondence, 1871-1884, 1892-1898 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Divinity School and Theological Department, 1888-1895 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Law School, 1872-1885, 1887-1898 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Library: correspondence, 1883-1890 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Library acknowledgements, 1891-1899 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Medical Department, 1884-1898 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Observatory and Horological Bureau, 1886-1891 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, 1881-1899 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Degrees: B.A., 1885-1899 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Degrees: Ph.B., Sheffield Scientific School, 1885-1895 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Degrees: undergraduate, 1893-1899 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Degrees: M.A., 1888-1893 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Degrees: M.A., 1888-1899 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Degrees: D.D., 1889-1899 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Degrees: LL.D., 1888-1895 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Degrees: B.F.A., M.A., and Ph.D., lists and regulations, 1889-1899 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Degrees: Honorary, 1870-1886 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Degrees: Honorary, 1872-1886 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Degrees: Honorary, 1893-1895 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Role of Honor: corrections, 1865-1866 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Invitations from other universities, 1889-1894 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Portraits: correspondence, 1833-1901 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Proposed statue of President Dwight: correspondence, 1870-1871 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Yale at the Centennial Exhibition: guest register, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 37)